A prime number is a positive integer, which is divisible on 1 and itself.
Any positive integer can be divided in primes in essentially only one way.

There is no largest prime number.

To prove this, let’s consider only n prime numbers: p1, p2, …, pn. 
But no prime pi divides the number

N = p1 * p2 * … * pn + 1,

so N cannot be composite. This contradicts the fact that the set of primes
is finite.

A no. cannot have more than 1 prime factors greater than sqrt(n).
If a no. is composite then it will atleast have one factor <= sqrt(n)(other than 1). or we can that it will have atleast one prime 
factor less than sqrt(n).

A modified version of seive running in nlogn time is to mark multiples of all the numbers (not only primes)

We can find the factors and  no. of factors AND prime factors and the no of prime factors of  a number n in sqrt(n) time(technique)(slightly greater).
We can find no. of primes and no. of prime factors of a no. less than n in nloglogn time by using modified sieve.

sum of divisors and no. of divisors formula:

We begin by writing the number as a product of prime factors: n = p^a.q^b.r^c...
then the number of divisors, d(n) = (a+1)(b+1)(c+1).

http://math.stackexchange.com/questions/22721/is-there-a-formula-to-calculate-the-sum-of-all-proper-divisors-of-a-number

Proper Factor: All factors of a number other than 1 and the number itself. For example. The number 6 has proper factors 2, and 3. 1 and 6 are also factors, 
but they are not proper factors. The number 16 has proper factors 2, 4, and 8.


After taking product of digits of a numbers , its prime factors can only be 2 3 5 7.

No. of primes till n ~ n/logn
Max no of prime factors of n =logn

Goldbach’s Conjecture:
For any integer n (n ≥ 4) there exist two prime numbers p1 and p2 such
that p1 + p2 = n.For example, for n = 10 we have two such pairs: 10 = 5 + 5 
and 10 = 3 + 7.

Dirichlet’s theorem about arithmetic progressions:
For any two positive coprime integers a and b there are infinitely many primes of the form a + n*b, where n > 0.

In number theory, Wilson's theorem states that a natural number n > 1 is a prime number if and only if
(n-1)! is congruent to -1 mod n.

That is, it asserts that the factorial (n - 1)! = 1*2* 3...... (n - 1) is one less than
a multiple of n exactly when n is a prime number.

A diophantine equation is one which variables are restricted to integers only.The most imp class are of the form
ax-ny=b; which are congruent to solving ax is congruent to b (modulo n)

An optimized version of sieve will be not to consider the multiples of two and three.

use of fermats little theorem and euler totient function.

zrzr-no of zeroes in the factorial of a number in logn time.

codemonk number theory 3

min prime factor and segmented seive -he3

1 and -1 are coprime to every number
 



